Monica,that was the best Thanksgiving dinner ever.
这真是史上最棒的感恩节大餐
It was so good. I think you killed us.
太好吃了 你把我们撑死了
I couldn't possibly eat another bite.
我连一口都吃不下了
I need something sweet.
我要吃甜的
Does anyone want to watch TV?
有人想看电视吗？ 好啊
Monica,your remote doesn't work.
摩妮卡，你的遥控器按不动
You have to lift it and point.
你得把它拿起来对准
Oh,forget it.
算了
Let's play that game where everyone says one thing they're thankful for.
你们知道吗？ 我们应该来玩感恩告白游戏
I am thankful for this beautiful fall we've been having.
我要说 感谢今年的秋天这么美
Very nice.
说得真好
The other day, I was at the bus stop...
那天我在等公车
...and this lovely fall breeze came and blew this chick's skirt up.
突然吹来一阵秋风 把一个女生的裙子吹了起来
Which reminds me, I'm also thankful for thongs.
对了，我还要感谢丁字裤
The One with the Thanksgiving Flashbacks
本集播出：“感恩大回顾”
rainystar压制iPod-MP4
It's not so much an underpant as a feat of engineering.
与其说它是内裤 不如说是一种伟大工程
It's amazing...
效果那么惊人
...how much they can do with so little material.
料子却那么少
And they play with your mind. Is it there? Is it not there?
它还会戏弄你 有穿吗？没穿吗？
Are you aware that you're still talking?
你知道你还在碎碎念吗？
Is anyone thankful for anything else besides a thong?
有没有人要感谢 丁字裤以外的东西？
I don't know. Am I more thankful for my divorce or my eviction?
我不知道要比较感谢离婚 还是被赶出来
And I didn't think you'd be able to come up with anything.
我还以为你会没得谢
I'm sorry. This is the worst Thanksgiving ever.
抱歉，这是最惨的一次感恩节
I am the king of bad Thanksgivings.
不行，我才是悲惨感恩节盟主
You can't swoop in with your bad marriage and take that away from me.
你不能挟失败的婚姻空降 抢了我的宝座
You're not going to tell about your parents' divorce again,are you?
你又要说你爸妈离婚的事了？
Come on! I want to hear it.
别这样嘛，我想听
It wouldn't be Thanksgiving without Chandler bumming us out.
没有钱德扫兴就不算感恩节了
It's a tradition,like the parade.
这跟游行一样是一项传统
If the parade decided it was gay and abandoned its family.
如果游行也出柜离家 抛妻弃子的话
“1978年感恩节”
Now,Chandler,dear...
钱德
...just because we're getting a divorce...
爸爸和我要离婚
...doesn't mean we don't love you.
并不代表我们不爱你
It just means...
只是代表...
...he would rather sleep with the houseboy than with me.
...他上床的对像是男仆 不是我
More turkey,Mr. Chandler?
小少爷还要火鸡吗？
Every time you tell that story, that guy's accent gets thicker and thicker.
你把那砘锏目谝 说得越来越重
So are he and your dad still together?
他们还在一起吗？
No. After they got their own place, the houseboy got his own houseboy.
没有，他们同居之后 男仆自己也有了男仆
Should have heard his accent.
你应该听听他的口音
You're right,yours is worse. You're the king of bad Thanksgivings.
你说得对，你的更惨 你是悲惨感恩节盟主
I've got one that's worse.
不一定，我有一次更惨
Really? Worse than, "More turkey,Mr. Chandler?"
惨过“小少爷还要火鸡”吗？
Did the little rich boy have a problem with the butler?
小少爷跟仆人有仇吗？
Yes,mine's worse!
对，我的更惨
“1862年感恩节”
More bandages!
还要绷带！
还要绷带
Please,can I get some more bandages in here?
再给我一些绷带
This man is
这个人快死…
Oh，no
不会吧
In this life,Phoebe.
今生的才算
Oh,this life. Oh,okay.
今生是吧
No,Chandler's is worse.
那钱德的比较惨
It must be cool remembering stuff like that.
记得前世的事一定很酷
I don't have any past-life memories.
我都没有前世的记忆
Of course,you don't,sweetie. You're brand-new.
当然没有，你是新生命
I know Monica's worst Thanksgiving.
我知道摩妮卡最惨的感恩节
Let's not tell this story.
那个就别提了 说嘛
I know!
我知道
It's the one where Joey got Monica's turkey stuck on his head.
就是摩妮卡的火鸡 卡在乔伊头上那次
Joey got a turkey stuck on his head?
什么？乔伊头上卡了只火鸡？
It's not like it sounds.
其实不是那样
It's exactly like it sounds.
其实就是那样
“1992年感恩节”
菲比？
What's going on?
乔伊？怎么了？
你看
Oh,my God!
我的天哪
I know!
我知道
It's stuck!
它卡住了
Step.
小心台阶
How did it get on?
它怎么会跑到你头上？
I put it on to scare Chandler.
是我套上去想吓钱德
Oh,my God! Monica's going to totally freak out!
天哪，摩妮卡一定会气死
Help me get it off!
那就赶快帮我拿下来
Plus,it smells really bad in here.
而且这里面好臭
Of course it smells bad. You have your head up a dead animal's ass.
当然很臭 你的头塞在动物尸体的屁股里
是摩妮卡
Did you get the turkey?
你替火鸡涂…
Oh,my God!
我的天哪
Who is that?
那是谁？
It's Joey.
乔伊啦
Is this supposed to be funny?
你在干什么？你是在搞笑吗？
It's not supposed to be funny. It's supposed to be scary.
不是搞笑，是吓人
Get that off now!
马上给我拿掉
I can't. It's stuck!
拿不掉，卡住了
It has to feed 20 people. They're not going to eat it off your head!
我不管，我爸妈的二十个客人 可不能就着你的头吃
Hold on.
先别急
Let's just all think.
大家一起想办法
I got it!
我知道了
You pull.
菲比， 你拉
I'll spread the legs as wide as I can.
我尽量把腿撑开
Now is not the time. Sorry.
乔伊，现在不要闹 对不起
Count to three. One...
好，数到三…一...
...two...
...二...
...three!
...三
It worked! I scared you! I knew it!
成功了！我吓到你了
I'm here,big guy.
大哥，我在这里
Yeah,you are!
我知道
I scared you!
我吓到你了
You did look like an idiot.
你看起来真的很白痴
I wasn't the only one who looked like an idiot.
白痴的不只是我
Remember when Ross tried to say "butternut squash"...
罗斯有一次想说冬南瓜
...and it came out, "squatternut bosh"?
结果讲成南冬瓜
Yeah,that's the same.
的确一样白痴
That's it. That's my worst Thanksgiving.
那就是我最惨的感恩节
That can't be the one Rachel meant.
等等，瑞秋说的不可能是那次
She didn't even know that happened.
她根本不知道那件事
So,what's yours?
所以是哪一次？ 哪一次？
I really don't want to tell this story.
我真的不想提这件事
Reliving pain and getting depressed is what Thanksgiving's all about.
讲嘛，重温悲惨的回忆 是感恩节的精神
For me,anyway.
至少我觉得是
And,of course,the lndians.
还有原住民的帮忙
Of all people,you do not want me to tell this story.
最不希望我提的绝对是你
What is that supposed to mean?
什么意思？
“1987年感恩节”
-Monica,I think Rachel's here! -I'll get it!
摩妮卡，应该是瑞秋来了 我来开
Happy Thanksgiving!
感恩节快乐
Not for me.
我不快乐
Chip and I broke up.
奇普和我分手了
Why?
为什么？
What happened?
怎么了？
My parents are out of town, and Chip was going to come over.
我爸妈不是要出门 奇普不是要来…
And you were going to give him...
对，你要给他...
...your "flower."
...你的花芯
Monica,can you just call it sex?
摩妮卡，你能不能直接说做爱
It really creeps me out when you call it that.
你那样讲让我浑身发毛
And by the way...
还有...
...while we're at it,a guy's thing is not called his "tenderness."
...在做的时候 男人的那里不叫他的温柔
Believe me.
相信我
Happy Thanksgiving.
瑞秋 感恩节快乐 你也是
天哪
Everyone...
各位
...this is Chandler.
这是钱德
My roommate...
我的室友...
...and lead singer of our band.
...兼我们乐团的主唱
罗斯
This is Monica.
这是摩妮卡
I'm Ross' little sister.
我是罗斯的妹妹
好
I'm so glad you could come.
欢迎你来
We've got plenty of food, so I hope you're hungry.
有很多吃的 希望你饿了
Chandler hates Thanksgiving and doesn't eat any Thanksgiving food.
妈，钱德痛恨感恩节 他不吃感恩节食物
I'm so glad you brought him here.
那还真是欢迎啊
I can make you some macaroni and cheese for dinner.
钱德 我可以帮你煮起司通心面
As long as the Pilgrims didn't eat it.
只要当年的清教徒没吃我就吃
Damn it!
讨厌
Does it feel weird around here now?
瑞秋，你会不会觉得怪怪的？
You know,since I've been away at college?
我去上大学不在了以后
Not really.
那倒不会
That's cool.
那就好
那你…
So that's Rachel,the girl you've been writing all those songs about?
她就是你那些歌的女主角瑞秋 对
Might want to rethink the lyrics to "She Feels Weird Since I've Been Gone."
你可能得修改那句 “我的离去令她浑身不对劲”
I cannot believe Chip dumped me for that slut Nancy Branson!
奇普居然为了那个花痴南茜 而甩了我
I am never going out with him again. I don't care how much he begs.
我再也不跟他约会了 他再怎么求我也没用
His begging days are over,now that he's with Nancy Branson.
他有了南茜，应该不会求你了
I've just had it with high-school boys.
你知道吗？我受够高中男生了
They're just silly.
他们只是些笨蛋
They're just silly,stupid boys.
他们全是些又笨又呆的小毛头
I'll start dating men.
我要开始跟男人交往
I'm sorry,Judy.
茱蒂，对不起
I couldn't find that bowl you and Jack were looking for.
我找不到你和杰克要的碗
Call them Mom and Dad,you loser.
叫爸爸妈妈吧，俗辣
摩妮卡
钱德
Did you like the macaroni and cheese?
起司通心面好吃吗？
It was great. You should be a chef.
很好吃，你应该去当厨师
好啊
Guess what.
你猜怎样？
All this stuff about Nancy being a slut was all a rumor.
南茜很花痴的传闻都是假的
Chip dumped her,and he wants to come over to my house!
所以奇普甩了她 他今天晚上想来找我
-That is so great! -I know.
太棒了 就是啊
Oh,gosh. Listen, if you and Chip do it tonight...
天哪，要是你和奇普晚上做了
...promise me you'll tell me everything.
你一定要把细节都告诉我
Totally. It's not that big a deal. We already kind of did it once.
那当然，其实也没什么 我们应该有做过一次
But now you'll definitely know whether or not you did it.
我知道，但这回你一定能确定
I know.
我知道
And Chip promised that this time it'd last at least for an entire song.
奇普还保证 这次会持续一整首歌的长度
I'm thinking of asking Rachel out tonight...
我晚上打算约瑞秋出去
...maybe playing her that song we wrote last week.
弹我们上周写的那首歌给她听
"Emotional Knapsack"? Yes. Right on!
“忧愁的背包”？ 对 漂亮
But don't take long. We're testing our fake lD's tonight.
不过不要拖太久 我们还要去试用假身分证
Right,Clifford Alvarez?
对吧，克里夫艾维瑞兹？
Listen,Roland Cheng...
听着，罗兰陈
...if things go well, I may be out with her all night.
如果一切顺利 我们搞不好不会回来
Dude,don't do that to me.
兄弟，别丢下我
It's cool,you can stay here. My parents won't mind.
没关系，你可以留下来 我爸妈不会介意
It's not that. I just don't want to be stuck here with your fat sister.
不是，我不想整晚 跟你的肥猪妹妹在一起
Why don't you finish off these pies?
摩妮卡，把这些派吃完吧
I don't have any more room in the fridge.
冰箱塞不下了
No,thank you.
不了，谢谢
Judy,you did it.
茱蒂，你成功了
She's finally full!
她终于吃不下了
I called you fat?
我说你肥？
-I don't even remember that. -Maybe it'd jog your memory...
我完全不记得 或许唱...
...if you guys played a little bit of "Emotional Knapsack."
...那首“忧愁的背包” 可以让你想起来
I'm so sorry. I really am.
对不起，真的
I was an idiot back then.
我那时候很愚蠢
I rushed the stage at a Wham concert, for crying out loud!
我还在“轰”的演唱会上 冲上台大叫
I can't believe you called her fat.
你居然说她肥
I can't believe you let George Michael slap you.
你居然让乔治麦可赏你耳光
I am really sorry.
真的很抱歉
That is terrible. I'm so sorry.
我太差劲了 真是对不起
That's not the Thanksgiving I was talking about.
其实我说的不是那次感恩节
Yes,it was.
就是
No,it was actually
不是，我说的是…
Thanksgiving's over. Let's get ready for Christmas.
感恩节结束，准备过圣诞节吧 谁要去买圣诞树？
I have the cutest Christmas story.
我有最可爱的圣诞节故事
We want to hear Monica's story.
我们想听摩妮卡的感恩节故事
Mine had a dwarf that got broke in half, but,you know,whatever.
我的故事里有小矮人断成两截 不过随便
“1988年感恩节”
You changed your major again?
瑞秋，你妈说你又转系了
I had to.
没办法
There was never any parking by the psychology building.
心理系馆旁边很难停车
瑞秋
Love your new nose! Jack.
你的新鼻子真漂亮 杰克
What？ Dr. Wolfson's an artist.
怎样？威尔森医生是个艺术家
He removed my mole cluster.
他帮我点掉一堆痣
Want to see?
你要看吗？
No! Please,let me.
我去开 不，让我去
Happy Thanksgiving.
感恩节快乐
Your hair sure is different.
你的发型变了好多
We were just talking about that.
我们刚才还在讲
We can't believe how stupid we used to look.
我们以前真的好蠢
Where's Monica?
摩妮卡呢？
She's upstairs.
在楼上
Come down,everyone's here!
摩妮卡，快下来，人都到齐了
Ross,Rachel...
罗斯，瑞秋
...and the boy who hates Thanksgiving.
和那个痛恨感恩节的男生
钱德
Oh,my God!
我的天哪
What's the matter?
怎么了？
Is there something on my dress?
我的衣服有脏东西吗
You look so different.
你变了好多好漂亮
Terrific.
That dress,that body....
那件裙子，那个身材
-Dude! -Sorry.
喂 抱歉
Yes,she's thin. It's wonderful.
对，摩妮卡瘦了，太好了
But we really want to hear...
但我们比较关心...
...about Ross' new girlfriend.
...罗斯的新女友
Her name is Carol.
好吧，她叫卡萝
She's really pretty and smart.
她很漂亮，很聪明
She's on the lacrosse team and the golf team.
她是长曲棍球和高尔夫球校队
Can you believe it?
很厉害吧？
She plays for both teams.
她两个校队都打
So I guess I'll see you at dinner.
钱德，那就晚餐见罗
-Dude! -Sorry.
喂 抱歉
Oh,my God!
天哪
That was so awesome.
真是酷毙了
You got him back for calling you fat.
你完全报了一箭之仇
He was drooling all over you.
他的口水流了满地
-That must have felt so great. -lt didn't.
感觉一定很过瘾 一点也不过瘾
What？
什么？
Yeah,I mean,I look great.
没错，我很漂亮
I feel great,and my heart's not in trouble anymore.
感觉很轻盈 心脏的毛病也没了
I just don't feel like I got him back.
但我还是觉得没报到仇
I just want to humiliate him.
我想狠狠的羞辱他
I want him to be naked,and I want to point at him and laugh.
我想让他光着身体 再指着他大笑
That,we may be able to do.
好，搞不好可以
How?
怎么做？
Guys tend to get naked before they're going to have sex.
男人要做爱之前都会脱光衣服
What?
什么？
I didn't work this hard and lose weight...
我这么努力瘦这么多
...just so I could give my flower to someone like him.
可不是为了把花芯给他那种人
First of all,if you keep calling it that, no one will take it.
好，第一，你再那样讲 保证没有人会要
And then second of all, you're not going to have sex with him.
第二，又不是要你来真的
You'll just make him think that you are.
只是要你误导他
也对
I'll throw him out in the yard,lock the door...
等他脱光了 我就把他赶出去锁上门
...and all our neighbors will just humiliate him!
让所有的邻居耻笑他
You'll definitely get him back.
那你就绝对报了仇
How do I make him think I want to have sex?
我要怎么误导他？
Here's what you do.
我知道了
Just act like everything around you turns you on.
假装什么都能让你兴奋
What do you mean?
什么意思？
Anything can be sexy.
就是什么都能挑动你
Like this dish towel.
像…像这条擦碗巾
This feels so good against my cheek.
它的触感好舒服
And if I get a little hot, I can just dab myself with it.
如果我热了就可以拿它来吸汗
Or I can bring it down to my side and run it through my fingers...
或是把它放在腿边
...while I talk to him.
边跟他说话边玩弄
I can do that.
这个我会
Good,good,good.
很好
Get busy. He's coming.
他来了
Hey,what's up?
你好
Could you make me some of that righteous mac and cheese like last year?
摩妮卡，你能不能帮我煮 去年那种通心面
I'd love to.
没问题
I love macaroni and cheese.
我好喜欢起司通心面
I love the way this box feels against my cheek.
我好喜欢这个盒子的触感
And I love carrots.
我好喜欢胡萝卜
Sometimes I like to put them between my fingers.
有时我喜欢把它们这样夹着
Like this.
像这样
And hold them down here while I talk to you.
然后放在腿边跟你说话
And,you know,if I get really hot...
觉得很热的时候…
...I like to pick up this knife.
...我喜欢拿起这把刀
And I put the cool steel...
把冰凉的刀身...
...against...
靠在…
...my body.
身上
Are you all right?
你还好吗？
I'm fine. Just...
我很好，只是…
Twenty-year-old male.
什么状况？ 20岁男性
He's got a severed toe on his right foot.
右脚拇趾被切到
Could you please not do that feet first?
别撞到他的脚好吗？
You know where his injury is. Severed toe,you just said it!
你明知他是拇趾被切到 你刚才也说了
It says the knife went through your shoe.
这里写说刀子刺穿鞋子
They're made of wicker!
那当然，他穿的是草鞋
Did you bring the toe?
断指带来了吗？
I have it right here on ice.
有，在这里冰着
Toes on Ice,coming soon to Madison Square Garden.
“冰上拇趾秀” 麦迪逊花园广场即将演出
Save your strength,man.
省点力气吧
Don't worry,son. We'll just reattach it and then....
放心，我们会把它缝…
What is it?
怎么了？
You brought a carrot.
你带了一块胡萝卜来
This isn't your toe. This is a small, very cold piece of carrot.
什么？ 这不是你的脚趾 这是一小块很冰的红萝N
You brought a carrot?
你带胡萝卜来？
Oh,my God!
天哪，
There's a toe in my kitchen.
我的厨房里有一截断趾
I'm sorry! I'll go get it!
对不起，我马上回去拿
All we can do now is sew up the wound.
来不及了，我们只能直接缝合
Without my toe? I need my toe!
我需要我的脚趾头
I can go really fast!  Dad, give me the keys to your Porsche.
等一下，我很快 爸，让我开你的保时捷
I'm not falling for that one.
我才不会上当
That's why I lost my toe? Because I called you fat?
这就是我断趾的原因？ 因为我说你肥？
I didn't mean to cut it off. It was an accident.
我不是故意的，那是意外
That's why for an entire year people called me Sir Limps-a-lot?
我就因为这样被叫了一整年的 跛脚趾头先生？
I'm sorry.
对不起嘛
It wasn't your whole toe.
又不是一整根脚趾头
Yeah,well,I miss the tip.
我少了趾尖
It's the best part.
趾尖最棒
It has the nail.
趾尖有指甲
钱德
Sir Limps-a-lot.
跛脚趾头先生
I came up with that.
那是我想出来的
You're a dork.
你好无聊
-I can't believe this. -I said I was sorry.
我真不敢相信 钱德，我都道歉了
"Sorry" doesn't bring back the piggy that cried all the way home.
道歉也换不回 我那思乡情切的小趾尖
It figures that something like this would happen today.
我就知道今天会发生这种事
I hate this stupid day and everything about it!
我恨感恩节和这一天的一切
I'll see you later.
回见
Wait.
等等
Come here.
过来
Is there anything I can do? Anything?
有什么我能做的吗？
Just leave me alone for a little while.
有，让我静一静
I'm a duck. I go quack-quack.
我是鸭子呱呱呱
I'm happy all the time.
一天到晚都快乐
Nice try.
别试了
Wait,wait,wait.
等等
Look,Monica
摩妮卡… 你看
This is not going to work.
没有用的
I bet this will work.
接下来绝对有用
You're so great.
你真绝
I love you.
我爱你
What?
什么？
Nothing. I said you're so great, and then I just stopped talking.
没事，我说“你真绝” 然后就没说话了
You said you loved me. I can't believe this!
你说你爱我，我真不敢相信
No,I didn't!
我没有
Yes,you did!
你有
No,I didn't!
我没有
You love me!
你爱我
No,I don't!
我没有
Stop it,stop it,stop it!
别再说了
“1915年感恩节”
Gauze!
纱布！
纱布!
I need to get some gauze in here!
这里需要纱布
Can I please get some more gauze?
请再给我一些纱…
This is getting ridiculous.
真是越来越扯了